<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-10T12:21:18-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Anya E. Vostinar</title><subtitle>The homepage of Prof. Anya E. Vostinar. I teach computer science and research the evolution of  symbiosis using digital evolution and agent-based modeling. I wrote the Symbulation platform.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New Paper - Symbiosis in Digital Evolution: Past, and Future</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/symbiosis/digital%20evolution/symbulation/2021/12/31/symbiosis-digital-evolution-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper - Symbiosis in Digital Evolution: Past, and Future" /><published>2021-12-31T09:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-31T09:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/symbiosis/digital%20evolution/symbulation/2021/12/31/symbiosis-digital-evolution-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/symbiosis/digital%20evolution/symbulation/2021/12/31/symbiosis-digital-evolution-review.html">&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post to announce the publication of a review article from this past fall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fevo.2021.739047/full&quot;&gt;Symbiosis in Digital Evolution: Past, Present, and Future&lt;/a&gt;.
The review is aimed primarily at ecologists and evolutionary biologists interested in how the technique/field of digital evolution can be used to investigate the evolutionary dynamics of symbiosis. 
However, a secondary audience that we kept in mind while writing are those already working in digital evolution and artificial life who are interested in the research space of symbiosis and a history of digital evolution through the lens of symbiosis.
I also generally aim to make all of my papers accessible to my undergraduate students, so I hope that it will be interesting and understandable to a wide range of readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights from the paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A history of symbiosis in digital evolution from the very beginning of the field, including some little-known digital evolution systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A middle-ground and extensively considered definition of digital evolution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A briefer discussion of the definition of symbiosis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A lovely figure depicting the main components of symbiosis in a hypothetical digital evolution system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An overview and synthesis of the findings regarding symbiosis found using digital evolution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A list of the current digital evolution software that supports symbiosis in some form and a comparison of their functionalities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A whole bunch of open research questions and directions about symbiosis that digital evolution is well-suited to investigate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A call for specific improvements and innovations in digital evolution software that will be necessary to push forward investigation into symbiotic dynamics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research" /><category term="Symbiosis" /><category term="Digital Evolution" /><category term="Symbulation" /><summary type="html">Just a quick post to announce the publication of a review article from this past fall Symbiosis in Digital Evolution: Past, Present, and Future. The review is aimed primarily at ecologists and evolutionary biologists interested in how the technique/field of digital evolution can be used to investigate the evolutionary dynamics of symbiosis. However, a secondary audience that we kept in mind while writing are those already working in digital evolution and artificial life who are interested in the research space of symbiosis and a history of digital evolution through the lens of symbiosis. I also generally aim to make all of my papers accessible to my undergraduate students, so I hope that it will be interesting and understandable to a wide range of readers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poster Sessions Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/symbulation/2021/12/17/poster-sessions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poster Sessions Update" /><published>2021-12-17T09:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-17T09:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/symbulation/2021/12/17/poster-sessions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/symbulation/2021/12/17/poster-sessions.html">&lt;p&gt;This past fall we had several posters of research from my lab and the ECODE lab that used Symbulation. 
It’s always awesome to see my undergraduate researchers explaining their projects to friends and family.
In addition, the ECODE lab poster was selected as one of 12 to be displayed during a trustee event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evolution-of-endosymbiosis&quot;&gt;Evolution of Endosymbiosis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/EndosymbiosisPoster.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of a research poster with a student standing by it.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first project is focused on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/anyaevostinar/Evolution-of-Endosymbiosis-Paper&quot;&gt;evolution of endosymbiosis&lt;/a&gt;. Piper Welch is in the photo above and did this work with Kiara Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evolution-of-beneficial-lysogeny&quot;&gt;Evolution of Beneficial Lysogeny&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/LysogenyPoster.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of a research poster with two students standing by it.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next project is focused on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/anyaevostinar/Evolution-of-Lysogeny-Paper&quot;&gt;evolution of beneficial lysogeny&lt;/a&gt;. Alison Cameron and Seth Dorchen worked on this project together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evolution-of-mutualism-with-multi-infection&quot;&gt;Evolution of Mutualism with Multi-Infection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/MultiInfectionPower.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of a research poster.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final project is from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecodelab.com/&quot;&gt;ECODE&lt;/a&gt; Lab and uses Symbulation. It is focused on how the evolution of mutualism changes when multiple endosymbionts can infect the same host.
This poster was selected to be one of 12 displayed during a recent dedication ceremony for the new science complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these projects have papers on the way, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research" /><category term="Symbulation" /><summary type="html">This past fall we had several posters of research from my lab and the ECODE lab that used Symbulation. It’s always awesome to see my undergraduate researchers explaining their projects to friends and family. In addition, the ECODE lab poster was selected as one of 12 to be displayed during a trustee event!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cheating Lessons Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/teaching/reading/2021/10/03/cheating-lessons1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cheating Lessons Part 1" /><published>2021-10-03T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-03T10:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/teaching/reading/2021/10/03/cheating-lessons1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/teaching/reading/2021/10/03/cheating-lessons1.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve previously read &lt;strong&gt;Small Teaching&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesmlang.com/&quot;&gt;James Lang&lt;/a&gt; and recommend it to all college professors.
So when the opportunity came up on campus to read another of Lang’s books and discuss it with a group of faculty, I couldn’t resist, despite a rather packed term schedule.
Here are my thoughts on part 1 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674724631&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cheating Lessons&lt;/strong&gt; by James Lang&lt;/a&gt;, in response to the reading questions provided by the facilitators of the group, Dave Musicant and Deborah Gross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lang presents, by our count, six features of a learning environment that
may pressure individuals into cheating:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;an emphasis on performance&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;high stakes riding on the outcome&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;extrinsic motivation for success&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;low expectation for success&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;perception of peer cheating behavior&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;perception of peer approval/disapproval of cheating&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Which of these features, if any, do you see as common at Carleton or in
your experience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The historical examples that Lang provides of situations where cheating was rampant definitely demonstrate the extremes of these features and these features nicely formalize hunches that I’ve had for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s going to be hard to escape some emphasis on performance and extrinsic motivation at any prestigious college, since it would be wrong to pretend that there aren’t some consequences for the grades that students get in our classes.
However, it seems like there is a movement away from some of the traditional forms of assessment that increase these features, such as one large final exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is this list complete?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that is missing from this list is the ease with which students can cheat, which does seem important to the discussion.
An in-person exam that would require active planning to cheat, such as smuggling in solutions, seems less likely to have cheating than a take-home exam where spontaneous cheating is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Are the items on the list intrinsically bad?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very interesting question and I think very much depends, as is always the case, on what moral code you use to judge ‘bad’. 
If you are coming from a base of “learning is good, not learning is bad”, Lang presents strong evidence that these things are bad because they decrease learning.
If you are coming from a base of “student mental well-being is good”, it seems clear that most of those items are bad since they put students under extreme mental pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes, there have to be high-stakes in life, and sometimes what matters really is the performance of the skill instead of the mastery, and sometimes you have to try for things that have a low chance of success (otherwise no one would every submit grant proposals!). 
So perhaps each individually is not intrinsically bad (except for the last two), but the combination of them can be a bad mixture, and when they can be reduced, that is for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The approach that Lang takes in writing this particular book is that of
focusing on what we can do in our own classrooms, and he largely defers
the campus-policy discussions for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Is this a direction we individually are interested in taking, i.e.,
taking steps in our own classes to help?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is definitely a direction that I am interested in taking, partially to reduce cheating, but partially also because I’ve been convinced by Lang that efforts to reduce the likelihood of cheating can also lead to better learning.
I’ve already reduced the stakes on any individual assessment (I don’t have final exams and instead have short quizzes throughout the term and a final project). 
I’ve also been trying to tackle the extrinsic motivation issue, which I find one of the most challenging, but also the most interesting. 
I realized a few years ago that I hate grading assignments that all do the same thing, and so individualizing assignments works for me as well as increasing the intrinsic motivation for the students.
That is sometimes a challenge with programming assignments, but I’m exploring ways of doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;To what extent is the answer education vs. policing, and to what
extent do we believe actions should be taken in our classrooms vs
campuswide?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure what campuswide action on these issues would look like. 
Policing definitely doesn’t seem like it will be as effective as education, as has been demonstrated in many other policing contexts (i.e. seeing others punishment doesn’t stop people from committing the crime). 
There could be some campuswide initiatives to decrease emphasis on GPA, such as abandoning &lt;em&gt;magna&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;summa cum laude&lt;/em&gt; or the Dean’s List, which just serve as a way of adding stress to students to get that A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some level of campuswide policy and policing is necessary to make it clear that cheating isn’t acceptable. 
And campuswide policy could impact the features of the culture at a campus level.
However, it is clear that Lang’s audience is teachers in the classroom, and it is nice to feel empowered to make a difference at a small scale immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anya&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Teaching" /><category term="Reading" /><summary type="html">I’ve previously read Small Teaching by James Lang and recommend it to all college professors. So when the opportunity came up on campus to read another of Lang’s books and discuss it with a group of faculty, I couldn’t resist, despite a rather packed term schedule. Here are my thoughts on part 1 of Cheating Lessons by James Lang, in response to the reading questions provided by the facilitators of the group, Dave Musicant and Deborah Gross.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ISAL Awards Eligible List</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/isal/2021/09/26/awards-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ISAL Awards Eligible List" /><published>2021-09-26T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-26T10:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/isal/2021/09/26/awards-list</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/isal/2021/09/26/awards-list.html">&lt;p&gt;Every year when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://alife.org/&quot;&gt;ISAL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://alife.org/about-isal/&quot;&gt;awards&lt;/a&gt; nomination form goes around, I stress because I both feel it is a duty to nominate but also &lt;strong&gt;can’t remember all the great papers and projects that I’ve seen during the year&lt;/strong&gt; and don’t have time to go find them all.
Some of the categories are also really difficult to systematically find eligible papers for, such as the award for best student paper, since I can’t easily if a scientist is at the right career stage for the award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also am generally &lt;strong&gt;intimidated at the idea of self-nominating&lt;/strong&gt; for the things that I’m eligible for, since what if I’m not actually good enough and the mysterious people who look at the nominations laugh at me?? (I’ve been told that I really shouldn’t worry about this, but my anxiety just won’t listen to me….)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try to improve some of these barriers to nominating, I’ve decided to make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QbvVeD3vvWRAY01gXxUnf8xja3bCJpw8g1_pNIGD31Y/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; for myself where I can collect the information for eligible people and projects throughout the year. 
I also decided to figure out how to set it up through Google so that &lt;strong&gt;others can also add to the spreadsheet&lt;/strong&gt; and it will automatically organize itself by award!
(Yes, I’m ridiculously proud of setting this up, please don’t judge me too much.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping that, since it is completely anonymous, it also will lower the anxiety bar about adding your own things to it.
&lt;strong&gt;Are you a student, or recently a student??&lt;/strong&gt; 
Please please please &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QbvVeD3vvWRAY01gXxUnf8xja3bCJpw8g1_pNIGD31Y/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;add your publications&lt;/a&gt; for the student paper award!
&lt;strong&gt;Are you an early career researcher?&lt;/strong&gt; (Usually considered pre-tenure.)
Then please &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QbvVeD3vvWRAY01gXxUnf8xja3bCJpw8g1_pNIGD31Y/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;add yourself&lt;/a&gt; for the Early Career award!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also hoping this will serve as a useful resource for lots of other things, like finding cool people and projects in the artificial life community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just remember that this &lt;strong&gt;isn’t the official nomination form&lt;/strong&gt; and you should make sure to actually submit nominations once that opens up as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the meantime, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QbvVeD3vvWRAY01gXxUnf8xja3bCJpw8g1_pNIGD31Y/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;add all the cool stuff&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,
Anya&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ISAL" /><summary type="html">Every year when the ISAL awards nomination form goes around, I stress because I both feel it is a duty to nominate but also can’t remember all the great papers and projects that I’ve seen during the year and don’t have time to go find them all. Some of the categories are also really difficult to systematically find eligible papers for, such as the award for best student paper, since I can’t easily if a scientist is at the right career stage for the award.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Recap September</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reading/2021/09/19/reading-sept.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Recap September" /><published>2021-09-19T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T10:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reading/2021/09/19/reading-sept</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reading/2021/09/19/reading-sept.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve added a number of interesting books and papers to my TBR pile lately and even started a couple of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;papers&quot;&gt;Papers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s13199-021-00794-0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbiosis and the Anthropocene&lt;/strong&gt; by Erik F. Y. Hom and Alexandra Penn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited about this paper for several reasons. 
The first is that Erik and Alex are both part of the ALife community and people that I really like as human beings.
The second is that this subject is such a fantastic mash-up of their two specialties and I love when scholars collaborate and find the awesome ways in which their research intersects.
And finally, I love any and all things symbiosis!
I haven’t had a chance to read the full manuscript, but from the abstract and intro, it sounds like it is full of great ideas for future research as well as important things to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/lichenologist/article/lichens-and-microbial-syntrophies-offer-models-for-an-interdependent-route-to-multicellularity/7770F423E1C309A1609C769C41F7A94C&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lichens and microbial syntrophies offer models for an interdependent route to multicellularity&lt;/strong&gt; by Eric Libby and William C. Ratcliff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love a good review (who doesn’t??), and this is one that I have had time to read. 
It is a great overview of how a multicellular organism could evolve from distinct species (an egalitarian transition) that has both specific examples and a good discussion of the existing theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780374159122/fourthousandweeks&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four Thousand Weeks: Time Management for Mortals&lt;/strong&gt; by Oliver Burkeman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started this one already, which says something about what’s on my mind lately!
I’ve gotten tired of the self-help time management books and am close to accepting that I can’t do everything that I want to do in my lifetime (haven’t quite given up yet though), so I’m hopeful that this book will be helpful in establishing the right perspective.
I’m only through the intro so far, but it is interesting and intriguing so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://davidepstein.com/the-range/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range: Why Generalists Triumph in a Specialized World&lt;/strong&gt; by David J. Epstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t started this one, but I have a sample downloaded to see if I like it. 
I’ve gotten skeptical of many of these kinds of pop science books, but I am a generalist by nature, so it might be nice escapism reading to make me feel better about constantly jumping between things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/W/bo15288825.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing Science in Plain English&lt;/strong&gt; by Anne E. Greene&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a Twitter trend going around of sharing books that you want all your new lab members to read and I grabbed several of these from those posts. 
This is one; I’m constantly on the hunt for science writing books and hadn’t seen this one before, which surprised me.
I haven’t started it yet, so I’m not sure at what level it is or if it will be a repeat of things I’ve already read, but we’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52373422-mushrooms-of-the-upper-midwest&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mushrooms of the Upper Midwest&lt;/strong&gt; by Teresa Marrone and Kathy Yerich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ve been getting into mushroom hunting this summer, though apparently it’s been a particularly terrible year for mushrooms in our area.
I’ve found this field guide helpful in that endeavor. 
It has a beginning section on mushroom morphology and the top six edible mushrooms, which are generally easy to positively identify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anya&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reading" /><summary type="html">I’ve added a number of interesting books and papers to my TBR pile lately and even started a couple of them!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dev &amp;amp; Doc: ReadTheDocs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/symbulation/2021/09/12/dev-doc-readthedocs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dev &amp;amp; Doc: ReadTheDocs" /><published>2021-09-12T08:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-12T08:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/symbulation/2021/09/12/dev-doc-readthedocs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/symbulation/2021/09/12/dev-doc-readthedocs.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy summer full of lots of new functionality in &lt;a href=&quot;https://anyaevostinar.github.io/SymbulationEmp/web/symbulation.html&quot;&gt;Symbulation&lt;/a&gt;!
I’ll be doing a blog post for each of these new features (and they’re already available in the code), but to give you a sneak peek:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lysis and Lysogeny support in Bacterium and Phage classes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free-living symbiont population&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PGGHost and PGGSymbiont classes that enable symbionts sharing a host to engage in a public goods game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new symbiont class with an ‘efficiency’ trait&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The possibility of setting the mutation rates and sizes separately for horizontal and vertical transmission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-documentation&quot;&gt;New Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s post, though is to highlight the new documentation put together by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/piper-welch-8357591aa/&quot;&gt;Piper Welch&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://symbulation.readthedocs.io/&quot;&gt;Symbulation’s documentation&lt;/a&gt; is now through ReadTheDocs and contains some exciting new additions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;projects-using-symbulation&quot;&gt;Projects Using Symbulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is now a page listing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://symbulation.readthedocs.io/en/latest/projects/index.html&quot;&gt;active and past projects&lt;/a&gt; that use Symbuluation. 
As you can see from it, we have several ongoing projects that we are excited about and we hope that more will continue to get added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-start-guides&quot;&gt;Quick Start Guides&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of quick start guides in the works, but currently there are now guides for getting Symbulation’s default setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://symbulation.readthedocs.io/en/latest/QuickStartGuides/1-GettingRunning.html&quot;&gt;running at the command line&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://symbulation.readthedocs.io/en/latest/QuickStartGuides/2-CollectingData.html&quot;&gt;collecting data&lt;/a&gt; with a little Python script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re planning on making many more guides that will be appropriate for an undergraduate who has taken a couple of CS classes, so let me know if there are particular things that you’d like to be prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future guides that I’m currently thinking about are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building and running the web version locally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a provided R script to get the data files into lovely plots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recreating the results from the major previous papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;library-api&quot;&gt;Library API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have most of the public methods for all the classes documented nicely and showing up in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://symbulation.readthedocs.io/en/latest/api/library_root.html&quot;&gt;auto-generated documentation&lt;/a&gt;.
Piper worked hard on getting them formatted so that they show up in a readable format. 
Our goal is for all of this documentation to be easily understandable when you are trying to use existing functions or make your own, so let us know if that isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contributing-to-symbulation&quot;&gt;Contributing to Symbulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have a set of guides on how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://symbulation.readthedocs.io/en/latest/dev/getting-started.html&quot;&gt;contribute to Symbulation&lt;/a&gt; that includes discussion of first-time setup, coding guides, documentation, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;philosophy&quot;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to take a final minute to discuss my philosophy behind this documentation and Symbulation in general.
There are several refactors of the internals of Symbulation coming up, first to organize the many classes that have been developed this summer, and then to port it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mabe2.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;MABE2&lt;/a&gt; when that is reasonable.
However, as with most refactoring, the goal is that external features will remain mostly the same (I can’t promise that that will be true with the MABE2 port, we’ll see).
Since I work with primarily undergraduates, a lot of this documentation is what I have to teach each year’s incoming students anyway, so it just makes sense to have it written down. 
While the current documentation hasn’t been stress-tested by new undergraduates yet, it will be in the coming year, and I’m looking forward to the improvements they will suggest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that all in mind, if you try to use the documentation and run into problems, please contact me either through email or GitHub, I really would love to improve any misunderstandings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anya&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research" /><category term="Symbulation" /><summary type="html">It’s been a busy summer full of lots of new functionality in Symbulation! I’ll be doing a blog post for each of these new features (and they’re already available in the code), but to give you a sneak peek: Lysis and Lysogeny support in Bacterium and Phage classes Free-living symbiont population PGGHost and PGGSymbiont classes that enable symbionts sharing a host to engage in a public goods game A new symbiont class with an ‘efficiency’ trait The possibility of setting the mutation rates and sizes separately for horizontal and vertical transmission</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Difficulties in controls in digital evolution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2020/12/24/difficult-controls.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Difficulties in controls in digital evolution" /><published>2020-12-24T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-24T10:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/2020/12/24/difficult-controls</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2020/12/24/difficult-controls.html">&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mitpressjournals.org/doi/full/10.1162/artl_a_00319&quot;&gt;The Surprising Creativity of Digital Evolution: A Collection of Anecdotes from the Evolutionary Computation and Artificial Life Research Communities&lt;/a&gt; by Joel Lehman and colleagues since I plan to include it in my class CS 361 Evolutionary Computing and Artificial Life this coming term. While reading, I was reminded of an experience that I had while working on my paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/ece3.5460&quot;&gt;Suicidal selection: Programmed cell death can evolve in unicellular organisms due solely to kin selection&lt;/a&gt; which I of course forgot all about when the call for this collection went out, but I am going to record now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work for that paper focused on the evolution of altruism where a digital organism could greatly harm itself (often to the point of death) in exchange for either helping its kin (organisms with close to matching genomes) or harm its non-kin. 
I am interested in how such a trait could evolve and at one point was trying to gain data from a control treatment where I forced the organisms to retain the detrimental behavior in an environment where it was not beneficial so that I could then know exactly how beneficial it was in the other environment.
This work was done in Avida, which has a rich set of behaviors that organisms can evolve, including instructions that allow organisms to skip over sections of their genome.
You can probably see where this is now going….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very confused why I wasn’t seeing any organisms being harmed by this behavior that I knew should definitely be harmful even though I was not allowing mutations that would remove the gene from their genomes.
In the end I carefully watched the gene-by-gene execution of the organisms and watched the skip happen so that they didn’t actually perform the behavior even though I wasn’t letting them get rid of it.
To get around this, I had to run offspring through a test environment to make sure that they actually performed the behavior before allowing them to be born.
I’m just glad I didn’t run into the scenario another Avida researcher did where the organisms learned how to fake out the test environment too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend the creativity in digital evolution paper I linked above for more excellent anecdotes that show that even in a system where you are supposed to have complete control, evolution is shockingly good at thwarting you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research" /><summary type="html">I just finished reading The Surprising Creativity of Digital Evolution: A Collection of Anecdotes from the Evolutionary Computation and Artificial Life Research Communities by Joel Lehman and colleagues since I plan to include it in my class CS 361 Evolutionary Computing and Artificial Life this coming term. While reading, I was reminded of an experience that I had while working on my paper Suicidal selection: Programmed cell death can evolve in unicellular organisms due solely to kin selection which I of course forgot all about when the call for this collection went out, but I am going to record now!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Things to change (eventually)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/teaching/2020/12/14/things-to-change.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things to change (eventually)" /><published>2020-12-14T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-14T10:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/teaching/2020/12/14/things-to-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/teaching/2020/12/14/things-to-change.html">&lt;p&gt;I historically have hated the idea of “there’s always room for improvement” and it’s only recently that I’ve thought carefully about why that is. I love the principles of Growth Mindset and have found them supremely helpful on my teaching journey, so it seemed weird that at the same time my skin crawled whenever someone talked about always wanting to improve. I eventually realized that it was perfectionism still sneaking its way in since if there was room for improvement, it wasn’t perfect, and it was unacceptable to ever offer a less than perfect class so I had to work myself to the bone to reach perfection immediately and then never need to improve again. If I could never reach perfection despite working myself to the bone, I would have to always work myself to the bone and damn is that a depressing thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now that I’ve identified perfectionism sneaking in again, I can fight it and aim for balance of trying to improve a few things each time I teach a class. That phrase ‘a few’ is quite important since I can’t improve everything at once and so by necessity, some things will have to be imperfect for now. Deciding which few things to improve this coming term is the point of this post, where I will attempt to list out the things popping around my brain for my class CS 201 Data Structures and weigh the pros and cons of focusing on that thing versus others. (In the spirit of avoiding perfectionism, there will be typos, enjoy!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Switch from Piazza to Moodle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce beginning of class formative polls/quizzes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reweight rubrics of the homeworks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop test suites for the homework and/or labs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop polished solutions for the labs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embrace spec/mastery grading scheme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change some of the homeworks to require inheritance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adjust the requirements of the homeworks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make more videos instead of readings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make reference sheets to go along with videos or readings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, this is good confirmation for why I can’t do everything I want to this coming term….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;switch-from-piazza-to-moodle&quot;&gt;Switch from Piazza to Moodle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a necessity really since Piazza has shifted to a paid and/or an advertising model and I’m just getting an icky feeling about continuing to use it given how they may or may not use my students’ data. Since I use Moodle as my LMS now, I will try out their forums for anonymous question and answer. I know a lot of colleagues that use Slack, but I like the anonymous option for an intro class (well, second class, but close enough).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be other options (Campuswire is the one I’ve heard of in addition to Slack), but I really don’t want to tackle a whole new tool and add it to students’ burden if a built-in one is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduce-beginning-of-class-formative-pollsquizzes&quot;&gt;Introduce beginning of class formative polls/quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided on this being my preferred way of &lt;a href=&quot;/teaching/2020/12/01/flipped-classrooms&quot;&gt;capturing students’ questions in a flipped classroom&lt;/a&gt;. It shouldn’t be too hard since I had daily quizzes last term that I think I will move to being here instead. There is still the issue of it taking potentially a lot of a short class period, but I was recently reminded that students are expected to do a whopping 15 hours of work for my class a week. Only 3.5 hours are in class, I expect an hour max on the reading or video for each day, so they have 8.5 hours left for the homework for the week and to finish their lab activities. (This does mean that they have to work on school 45 hours a week if they take three classes, which is rather problematic….)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a small addition of work on my part that I think will be a large gain for students in that they will get more questions answered because they will ask more questions. I will also be putting homework questions on these polls to motivate them to start reading the homework assignment early!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reweight-rubrics-of-the-homeworks&quot;&gt;Reweight rubrics of the homeworks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is expected the first time you teach a course, I realized after the fact that some of the rubrics I came up with for homework assignments allowed students to get near full credit without doing the things that really mattered. At first I was thinking of trying out a tiered rubric for each homework assignment (&lt;a href=&quot;/classes/201-w21/example-tiered-rubric&quot;&gt;example tiered rubric here&lt;/a&gt;), but discussion with colleagues firmed up the worry that a student would not realize they messed up an early tier and then not get credit for all the work on a later tier, which would lead to, well, tears. Without allowing for unlimited corrections, I don’t see the tiers working. Instead, I could just reweight the rubrics so that the core concepts are worth 70% of the points, so if a student messes up the core concept, they still get credit for the other things they did, but they can’t get an A on that assignment. Obviously the goal would be to not run into the situation of a student messing up the core concept, and I hope that more weight being on that will motivate them to ask questions instead of just push through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would require a bit of work to redo the rubrics but not a ton. The downsides from the student-perspective of 70% of points going to a small set of core concepts is that if a student isn’t getting that concept, they won’t be able to get as high of a grade, but if a C means “able to go on to the next class”, that means they really do need to get a handle on those core concepts. I think this is a worthwhile adjustment to make this coming term and captures what I really wanted from the tiered rubric without as much of the giant potential downside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;develop-test-suites-for-the-homework-andor-labs&quot;&gt;Develop test suites for the homework and/or labs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is always frustrating when a student submits code that they think works perfectly but in fact has a major logical error. Test suites would be handy for grading (though not everything can be checked with a test suite) and I generally follow the principle of transparency where if I have a test suite for my graders to grade with, I might as well give it to my students so they know exactly how they will be graded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several downsides to providing test suites however. One is just the time involved in making them, which isn’t insignificant, though also shouldn’t be too much more than is already spent when grading the assignments. Since we are theoretically using Repl.it, I might even be able to have them run automatically, what a concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another, however, is pedagogical. As soon as you give students a test suite, they stop thinking about how they know if their code is working correctly and start just trying things and seeing if they pass the test suite. At a 200 level, I think that might be okay. Learning how to test their code is not a learning objective of the course, though you might make a very good argument that it is a part of developing medium-sized projects and problem-solving in general. If I get fancy and have Repl.it run the tests, I could report to students if they pass the tests, but nothing more about the tests, so they would still have to think about how their code is working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking of a compromise where I provide a partial test suite, and clearly state that it is only partial, so that errors on the core concepts can be caught and (hopefully) corrected, but to get all the points on a homework, they have to test their code themselves. This has both pedagogical benefits and means less work in test development for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll aim for partial test suites on the homework, of which there are only 8, rather than the labs, of which there are 25+….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;develop-polished-solutions-for-the-labs&quot;&gt;Develop polished solutions for the labs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A request of some students last term was solutions for the labs (of which, remember, there are 25+). I didn’t want to hand out rough solutions from both a pedagogical perspective and, honestly, pride. If I’m going to give students solutions, I want to be sure that they are reasonably done and well commented and styled. Students will obviously look to those solutions as examples as they code, so I would want them to be damn good examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be a pretty serious time commitment if I were to do all of the labs. Some of them I already have a rough solution to that I would just need to polish, but some of them I was much more rushed when developing and so don’t actually have complete solutions at the moment. It would doubtless be good to have polished solutions that I was confident in. I also have pretty poor memory and so do like to redo the labs each term within a week of guiding students through them so that I actually remember how they are to be solved and focusing on developing more polished solutions could be a good use of that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embrace-specmastery-grading-scheme&quot;&gt;Embrace spec/mastery grading scheme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the dream, but definitely not feasible this term. Starting on the test suites will be a step in this direction since unlimited corrections/redos is a central tenant to this scheme and I don’t have the grading time for that without autograding. A lot of my other goals are trying to tackle small things that will make this dream feasible in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certainly pros and cons to mastery grading, a big one being that a difference in grades often gets turned into a difference in time investment on the students’ part which can be argued as good or bad. Given my goal is to assist every student in meeting their own goals in the course, I’m all right with that trade off. Given it often leads to higher grades because students can work at something until they master it and get that B or A they are aiming for, this is slightly risky depending on expectations of the institution. Fortunately for me, it sounds like my institution is pretty okay with high grades, or at least no one will come knocking on your door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;change-some-of-the-homeworks-to-require-inheritance&quot;&gt;Change some of the homeworks to require inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is clearly not an order to these ideas since we’ve swung from huge undertaking back to small, reasonable task. Sorry, not sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I settled on a final project that had to incorporate inheritance as a central mechanism since that is a pretty core concept of object-oriented programming in Java and a thing that differentiates it from other styles of programming. However I realized that none of the homework after HW2 actually required inheritance, which is… less than ideal in my mind. Given my very nice wiggle word ‘some’, this is an achievable task assuming there is a week somewhere that I don’t feel completely overwhelmed. I will endeavour to keep my eye out for a homework to sneak inheritance in again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adjust-the-requirements-of-the-homeworks&quot;&gt;Adjust the requirements of the homeworks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grades this past term ended up a little bit higher than desired (“desired by whom?” excellent question that I will conveniently ignore). This is because I was erring on the side of cutting students slack given the current world situation. Even though the world will be the same spot next term, I do feel that I should increase the requirements on the homework slightly. I think I will have my own mental image be that the requirements I currently have will be the B level requirements and I’ll add another thing for the last few points to reach an A. This thinking goes hand-in-hand with my reweighting of the rubrics to be 70% the core concepts and then the last 30% the extra things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This improvement has the benefit lacking in others that if I run out of time in a given week, I can leave that week’s homework as is and no one will be the wiser! If I was doing full test suites, this improvement would conflict with them (do I do the test suite first and then adjust requirements and adjust the test suite??), but if I stick with partial test suites, the added requirement wouldn’t need to be covered anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-more-videos-instead-of-readings&quot;&gt;Make more videos instead of readings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was another main request from the previous term’s students. I had some videos at first before hitting the time wall and needing to cut somewhere and videos got cut. I also realized that videos about code aren’t super helpful since students can’t easily refer back to the video during class, as opposed to readings which are easy to refer back to. If I make videos, I will only make them for topics where it is generally a conceptual topic and there isn’t syntax that students will need to refer back to. I definitely will not make any promise about a video for every class period and I am going to spend more time at the beginning of the term explaining this exact reasoning to my students. There are a few places though that I would love to explain the concept to students and then have them write the code instead of giving them a reading that has all the code already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-reference-sheets-to-go-along-with-videos&quot;&gt;Make reference sheets to go along with videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every term I encourage students to make their own cheat sheets/reference sheets from the readings and I don’t think I’ve ever seen it really happen. Maybe once. Since I like doing coding labs where students solve a problem during class time, if I do videos that do have code, I might make a reference sheet that they can use during the associated lab. I will state clearly on the sheet that it isn’t a substitute for watching the video and it will have basically no explanation, so that it only makes sense if you fully understood the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is a pretty low priority since I probably just won’t make videos that involve code because I use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opendsa-server.cs.vt.edu/&quot;&gt;OpenDSA textbook&lt;/a&gt; and it is pretty solid for most things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that I basically just decided to do all these things, which isn’t a good plan. I’m going to attempt to prioritize things now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piazza to Moodle - because I basically have to and it’s just set up before the term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beginning of class polls - this is minimal extra work and I hope will lead to much improved question/discussion time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reweight rubrics of the homeworks - I really want to emphasize the core concepts of the course and have the grading of the homework reflect that emphasis and this shouldn’t be too much work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop polished solutions for the labs - While I’m skeptical if any student will actually look at these, it would be a good thing to do to help me prepare for class anyway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop partial test suites for the homework - This is a fairly big ask that will help and hurt learning, though I think it will help the students who a struggling more, which is generally my philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase the requirements of the homeworks - While I do think I need to do this eventually, it is a fairly high cognitive load (since I want them to be meaningful additional requirements) and seems anti-thetical to best practices in the current world situation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change some of the homeworks to require inheritance - This is really 6.5 since it would go along with 6, though it would be a core concept and therefore in the 70% points section&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make more videos instead of readings - The OpenDSA textbook is pretty darn great, so I just don’t think most of the videos I could make would be helpful. I will record the beginning of class discussions, so I’m half doing this already&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make reference sheets to go along with videos - If I some day have so much time that I decide to make videos about code, I will do this, but that is not this term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mastery grading scheme - a lot of the previous things will need to happen first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record, I’m super unsure and conflicted about the ordering of 4-7 and probably will end up doing some later priority items on a wild hair (hare?). I don’t even know where to draw the line of how many of these things is reasonable to try. If you actually read this sentence and have an opinion, feel free to reach out and let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Teaching" /><summary type="html">I historically have hated the idea of “there’s always room for improvement” and it’s only recently that I’ve thought carefully about why that is. I love the principles of Growth Mindset and have found them supremely helpful on my teaching journey, so it seemed weird that at the same time my skin crawled whenever someone talked about always wanting to improve. I eventually realized that it was perfectionism still sneaking its way in since if there was room for improvement, it wasn’t perfect, and it was unacceptable to ever offer a less than perfect class so I had to work myself to the bone to reach perfection immediately and then never need to improve again. If I could never reach perfection despite working myself to the bone, I would have to always work myself to the bone and damn is that a depressing thought.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Structuring Flipped Classrooms</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/teaching/2020/12/01/flipped-classrooms.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structuring Flipped Classrooms" /><published>2020-12-01T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-01T10:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/teaching/2020/12/01/flipped-classrooms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/teaching/2020/12/01/flipped-classrooms.html">&lt;p&gt;Even though I’m teaching remote/online, I still am trying for a flipped classroom structure where my students read or watch videos before class and then spend classtime working on hands on activities so that they can ask questions when they get stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A problem I’ve run into is if I have time for students to ask questions at the beginning of class, they’ll often have forgotten what their questions were when they did the reading days ago and so they wish for a mini-lecture to remind them of their questions.
I don’t want to use up valuable classroom time with me just talking, so the choices I’ve thought of are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capture their questions beforehand with a form, ideally allowing it to be anonymous and them to be able to upvote other students’ questions if they have the same&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clicker quiz/poll to check their understanding and then if they are wrong, that is a good thing to revisit right away&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rely on the activity to bring up their questions eventually&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capturing-their-questions&quot;&gt;Capturing their questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally anonymously and with an upvote mechanism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can prepare answers ahead of time if it’s something that I don’t know off the top of my head&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They can see others’ questions and therefore realize that others have questions too and possibly realize a question they didn’t realize they had&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When do I cut off submitting new questions?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If right before class starts, I lose the pro of preparing answers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If further before class, some people might not be able to post their questions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I might not get any questions submitted even if students have them since typing out a question might be more than they feel like doing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to prepare pretty far ahead of time, so the idea of having to rush to prepare answers right before class stresses me out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students who don’t feel like doing the reading/watching the video aren’t pressured to do so and this could further encourage them not to because they think they can just listen to my answers for the important stuff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would need to find technology to support my ideal situation of upvoting and anonymous questions and hope that I can integrate it nicely, maybe Moodle has something already?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clicker-quizzes&quot;&gt;Clicker quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros-1&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can get a better idea if students really understand the material&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students are encouraged to prepare since they want to be able to answer the questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students who don’t do the preparation are revealed anonymously unless they’re really good at guessing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can craft the possible answers to highlight common misconceptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can prep ahead of time and reuse the quizzes, will already know what I will need to explain because I wrote the questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prompts students’ other questions since it jogs their memory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m pretty sure Zoom’s Poll functionality does what I want, but I need to try it out still&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons-1&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Difficult to write really good multiple choice questions that get at misconceptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Takes a fair amount of time to go through the polling and then discuss the answers/misconceptions; this isn’t wasted time of course as long as the questions are about important concepts, but it does take away from the hands-on activity in an already short class period&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students might still think they don’t need to prepare and will just learn the important things from the discussion, but at least I’ll know most likely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any kind of quiz, even an ungraded one, may feel stressful to students&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only works for students who are able to attend synchronous class, which isn’t all of my students right now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rely-on-the-activity&quot;&gt;Rely on the activity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros-2&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No additional preparation other than making a good activity, which I was already aiming for&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No additional class time required&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can talk through students’ questions one-on-one during the activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encountering a question in context of actual problem/code might be helpful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I generally try to structure the activity so that students answer some of their own questions because they can see what their code does or what works/doesn’t work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students working on the activity asynchronously can ask me questions over email&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be used in conjunction with other methods still&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons-2&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Misconceptions may linger as students cargo code or muddle through&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students aren’t pressured to read ahead of time because they can just refer to the reading/skim during the activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students may not ask me their question even one-on-one if they aren’t comfortable doing so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;verdict&quot;&gt;Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’m leaning toward trying out Zoom’s poll functionality to see if it recreates clicker quizzes sufficiently and then starting to craft those questions. I may not have a clicker quiz every class period if I can’t think of good questions, but it’s a start at least.
For in-person questions, I wouldn’t actually use clickers, I just used pieces of paper with four colored circles marked A-D that students would fold.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Teaching" /><summary type="html">Even though I’m teaching remote/online, I still am trying for a flipped classroom structure where my students read or watch videos before class and then spend classtime working on hands on activities so that they can ask questions when they get stuck.</summary></entry></feed>